Ahmed Muntasir Hossain

CSCI 2215

2 - Response

a - Cover Letter

November 26, 2020

Connecticut Blood Bank 7 Old Sherman Turnpike, Danbury, CT 06810

Dear Hiring Manager,

I am interested about the Database Administration position at CT Blood Bank. I am an upcoming Computer Science junior at the University of New Haven. I heard of CT Blood Bank through Guru. This position would provide me the opportunity to improve my skills in the field and gain experience in other sectors such as project management, and data analysis.

I am quite adept and comfortable using MySQL since I had to create complex programs to query databases. Additionally, I have experience in C, C++, and Java. I created small 3D games in Unity using C# to develop my creative ability and expand my programming knowledge. Moreover, I completed independent projects, a Payroll System in C++, and a Banking System in C. These projects have improved my ability to think holistically about a problem making me a suitable candidate for this position.

My interest in Machine Learning and Data Science has also led me to conduct a 2-month study under a faculty mentor to develop three machine learning classifiers that would predict heart disease with reliable accuracy using Weka, an open source machine learning software. As an undergraduate researcher, I identified the optimal number of attributes required to produce a comprehensive diagnosis and their impact on heart disease during my research. I used a similar methodology for another research paper where I analyzed survey data (qualitative and quantitative) to find common themes and presented the results in Excel. These projects have improved my ability to work individually and manage projects in a timely manner. I have also developed the ability to think critically and come up with specific solutions to problems.

I would really appreciate the opportunity to discuss my qualifications and the position further. Please contact me at (203) 390-0518 or ahoss1@unh.newhaven.edu. Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely, Ahmed Muntasir Hossain

b – Resume

Ahmed Muntasir Hossain

West Haven, CT | (203) 390-0518 | Ahoss1@unh.newhaven.edu www.linkedin.com/in/muntasirhossain314 | https://github.com/muntasir-hossain314159

PROFILE

Computer Science undergraduate student with strong communication and analytical skills with a passion for problem solving and gaining new knowledge. Able to facilitate and communicate effectively in teams. Experience as manager and organizer of multiple projects and events. Interested in software engineering and database management systems.

EDUCATION

University of New Haven

West Haven, CT

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

May 2023

Presidential Scholarship (Nov. 2018), Dean's Scholarship (Mar. 2019),

GPA: 4.00

Annual Honors Scholarship and Honors Program (Apr. 2019), Dean's List (Jan. 2019 & June 2020),

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, MySQL, NI LabVIEW
- Software: Weka, AutoCAD, Autodesk Inventor, West Point Bridge Design
- General: Operating Systems, Computer Architecture, Data Structures & Algorithms

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

University of New Haven

West Haven, CT

Summer Undergraduate Research Fellowship

June 2020-Aug. 2020

- Developed 3 machine learning algorithms on Weka that predicted heart disease reliably
- Determined minimum number of attributes required to obtain a comprehensible diagnosis using Relieff algorithm
- Determined the impact and relationship of attributes on predicting heart disease

University of New Haven

West Haven, CT

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Mar. 2020-Apr. 2020

- Reviewed, displayed, and analyzed post-event survey data from faculty trainings in the Makerspace to find maker ability, intended plans, and concerns
- Implemented the qualitative data analysis-technique of thematic coding, which determines common themes in written free-response answers.

LEADERSHIP

University of New Haven

West Haven, CT

24-Hour Innovation Investigation

Mar. 2020-Mar. 2020

- Developed an original prototype for a colorblind stop light, which acquired 1st place in the competition
- Improved interpersonal communication skills through working with a new team
- Surveyed and collected data for the model which underwent several iterations
- · Rapid prototyped final optimal model which was presented to judges

University of New Haven Global Student Leader

West Haven, CT

Jan. 2020-Present

 Provided support and guidance to new incoming international students, and organized social events to help students connect with their peers

University of New Haven

West Haven, CT

Team Manager, Manufacturing and Robotics Project

Sept. 2019-Dec. 2019

- Built and programmed an NXT EV3 Robot using LabVIEW to pick up an object in a preassigned location, drop it off at a particular destination and return to home base after completion.
- Weekly Presentation with updates of our work and a Final Presentation where the Robot would be tested

WORK EXPERIENCE

ChargerREC – David A. Beckerman Recreation Center

West Haven, CT Aug. 2020-Present

Member Service Attendant

- Check in members at the front desk
- Perform daily cleaning duties and enforce social distancing policies to ensure that our members are safe

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

St. Jude Children's Research Hospital

West Haven, CT

Worked as a fundraising volunteer at multiple St. Jude Rallies

Feb. 2020-Feb.2020